到目前为止，我们所有的响应都返回 html
up to this point all of our responses are returned html
但是假设我们要返回 json
but let's say we want to return json
对于 api 请求
for an api request
很好地做到这一点
well to do that
我们将使用一个外部 json 库，它不是
we'll use an external json library that's not
内置在长生不老药中
built into elixir
现在让我们这次开始有点不同
now let's start a little differently this time
这是一个表达我们想要的测试
here's a test that expresses what we want to have
当我们收到对 api 熊的请求时发生
happen when we get a request for api bears
我们想用内容类型的应用程序来响应
we want to respond with a content type of application
json 然后
json and then the
body 是一个 json 对象的列表，表示
body is a list of json objects representing
所有的熊
all the bears
再次不用担心输入这个
again don't worry about typing this in
你会在笔记中找到这个测试
you'll find this test in the notes
现在让测试通过
now to make the test pass
我们需要一种方法来编码被击中的熊的列表
we'll need a way to encode the list of bear struck
作为json
as json
并且 elixir 没有执行此操作的模块
and elixir doesn't have a module that does this
所以我们需要使用一个外部的 json 库
so we'll need to use an external json library
elixir 的包管理器叫做 hex，它是在 hex
elixir's package manager is called hex and it's at hex
pm 然后我们搜索encode json
pm and then we'll search for encode json
和他们的第一个结果
and their first result
这是一个名为毒药的图书馆
here is a library called poison
我们将继续使用它
and we're going to go ahead and use that
因为它很受欢迎
because it's very popular
和
and
Phoenix 也默认使用它进行 j 声音编码
also Phoenix uses it by default for j sound encoding
你注意到这里
you notice over here
它实际上
it actually
为我们提供了需要放入混音的代码
gives us the code we need to put in our mix
ex 文件，所以让我们继续复制它
ex file so let's go ahead and copy that
然后回到我们的项目
and then back over on our project
我们会打开 mix ex 你会记得的
we'll open up mix ex and you'll remember
这是我们可以确定我们的项目的地方
this is where we can figure our project
在其任何依赖项中
in any of its dependencies
所以我们将在此处添加该代码
so we'll add in that code down here
在深处，这是我们列出的地方
under depths this is where we list
依赖项
the dependencies
所以在这个里面
so inside of this
列表我们将粘贴我们复制的代码
list we'll just paste that code that we copied
如果您有其他项目依赖项
if you have other project dependencies
您只需在此处列出它们
you would just list them here
你注意到每个
and you notice that each
列表的元素是一个元组
element of the list is a tuple
第一个在哪里
where the first
元组的值是库的名称
value of the tuple is the name of the library
元组的第二个值是版本
and the second value of the tuple is the version
所以这表明我们想要毒包
so this indicates that we want the poison package
主要版本为三个
with a major version of three
和一个或更高版本的次要版本
and a minor version of one or greater
如果我们保存它
and if we save that
离开并回到命令行
away and come back over to a command line
我们可以运行混合深度来列出依赖项
we can run mixed depths to list the dependencies
它说好的你依赖毒药
it says okay you've got a dependency on poison
但它还不可用
but it's not yet available
运行混合深度得到
run mixed depths get
所以让我们继续做吧
so let's go ahead and do that
你注意到它变成了 hex rep 并且
you notice it goes off to the hex rep and
下载毒药 3 1 0
downloads poison 3 1 0
现在如果我们再次运行混合深度
now if we run mixed depths again
它说好的它被锁定在 3 1 0
it says okay it's locked at 3 1 0
但它已经过时了，你需要编译它
but it's outdated and you need to compile it
好吧，它将自动编译
well it's going to get automatically compiled
当我们运行应用程序时
when we run the application
所以我们有我们需要的一切
so we've got everything we need
事实上，如果我们查看这个目录
in fact if we look in this directory
有一个混合锁
there is a mix lock
这就是它记住哪个版本的地方
and that's where it remembers which version
所以它基本上锁定了那些版本依赖
so it basically locks down those version dependencies
我们还看到我们有这个目录叫做
we also see that we have this directory called
深度，我将在这里使用树实用程序
depths and I'm going to use the tree utility here
只是想看看是什么
just to see what's
在里面，你注意到在深处
inside of it and you notice inside of depths
我们有一个名为毒物的目录，它是库
we have a directory called poison that's the library
它有一个 lib 目录毒物
it has a lib directory poison
然后我们得到了那个库的长生不老药代码
and then we've got the elixir code for that library
所以这只是一个长生不老药应用
so this is just an elixir application
让我们快速旋转一下毒药库
let's give the poison library a quick spin
并混合看它是如何工作的
and mix to see how it works
你注意到我什么时候开火了
and you notice when I fired that up
它继续编译
it went ahead and compiled
毒药文件
the poison file
所以我们有了
so we've got that
现在让我们来点熊
now let's get some bears
好吧，这是我们熊市的名单
all right that's a list of our bears as bear struck
然后将它们转换为 json 我们使用毒药
and then to convert those into json we use poison
这是模块的名称
that's the name of the module
代码中调用了一个函数
there's a function called in code
结尾有一个感叹号
and it has an exclamation market the end
这意味着如果出现错误，它会引发异常
which means it raises an exception if there's an error
然后我们将它传递到我们的打击列表中
and then we just pass it in our list of struck
我们得到的是一个列表
what we get back is a list of
json 对象就像我们想要的一样
json objects just like we want
所以这是完美的
so this is perfect
现在我们知道如何将熊编码为 json
now that we know how to encode the bears as json
我们的 api 只需要一行和一个控制器
we simply need a row and a controller for our api
并且因为通常的做法是有一个单独的
and since it's common practice to have a separate
api请求控制器
controller for api requests
我们将在 api 目录中创建一个新控制器
we'll create a new controller in an api directory
在这里创建目录不值得的api
create the directory here undeserving api
这只是表明你可以
and this just demonstrates that you can
组织代码
organize code in
任意目录
arbitrary directories
它就在 lib 调查 api 下
it's just under lib survey api
你可以在这里有其他目录
and you can have other directories under here
然后在 api 目录中
and then inside of the api directory
我们想要一个名为 Bear 的文件
we want a file called bear
控制器前
controller ex
所以我们在 api 下有一个裸控制器
so we've got a bare controller under api
我们还有一个裸控制器正在调查中
we also have a bare controller just under survey
但他们会有所不同
but they're going to be different
因为该模块将被称为服务
because the module is going to be called serve
api 裸控制器，所以这反映了
api bare controller so this reflects
这里的目录结构
the directory structure over here
然后我们需要在这里定义一个动作
and then we need to define an action in here
我们将使用索引
and we're going to use index
这需要 co 和 v
it's going to take co and v
就像我们常规的熊控制器中的索引一样
just like the index in our regular bear controller
然后我们想生成一些 jason
and then we want to generate some jason
我们要说 json 等于
we're going to say json equals
我们将使用服务狂野的东西
we're going to use serve wild things
列出熊来获取我们所有的熊
list bears to get all of our bears
然后我们只是要把它变成毒药
and then we're just going to pipe that into poison
编码
encode
这将给我们返回 json
and that'll give us back json
然后我们需要返回一个更新的 co 和 v 地图
and then we need to return an updated co and v map
状态为 200
with a status of 200
然后是我们的响应体
and then our response body
将是杰森
will be jason
我们需要的第二件事是路线
the second thing we need is a route
所以如果我们去处理程序
so if we go to handler
我们可以复制斜线熊的路线
we can just copy the route we have for slash bears
然后修改它
and then modify it
是的，我们想匹配
yeah we wanted to match
api 斜线熊
api slash bears
然后而不是调用熊控制器索引
and then instead of calling the bear controller index
我们要打电话
we're going to call
调查api熊控制器索引
survey api bear controller index
你可以把它存起来
you can save that away
所以现在如果我们运行我们的测试会发生什么
so now what happens if we run our tests
如果我们在这里向上滚动，我们会遇到一次失败
what we've got one failure if we scroll up here
我们看到的红色
what we see in red that
我们正在返回文本 html
we're returning text html
但我们期待申请
but we're expecting application
json 所以内容类型不适合 api
json so the content type isn't right for api
要求我们应该
requests we should
始终将内容类型设置为应用程序 json
always be setting the content type to application json
好吧，这很容易解决
well this is easy enough to fix
我们只需设置内容类型
we'll just set the content type
在 co 和 v 结构中
in the co and v structure
我们将添加一个新的响应内容类型字段
we'll add a new response content type field
并将其默认为文本 html
and default it to text html
作为练习
as an exercise
你可以命名这个响应头
you could name this response headers
并在地图中保留任意响应标头
and keep arbitrary response headers in a map
但我们将通过使用使其保持简单
but we'll just keep it simple by using
响应内容类型和此处的字符串
response content type and a string here
所以现在我们有了
so now that we have that
我们需要回到我们的处理程序模块
we need to come back over to our handler module
我们需要改变
and we need to change
格式响应而不是硬编码文本 html
format response instead of hard coding text html
我们需要插值
we need to interpolate
合作和诉
co and v
响应内容类型
response content type
我们将保存它，cnv 也需要保存它
we'll save this and cnv need to save that off too
然后我们将转到我们的 api 裸控制器
and then we'll head over to our api bare controller
然后在这里我们将覆盖
and then here we'll just override
响应内容类型为应用程序 json
response content type to be application json
因此所有其他操作都将默认为
so all the other actions will take the default of
text html，但这个会覆盖它，因为
text html but this one's going to override it because
它正在返回 json
it's returning json
如果我们把它保存起来，测试现在应该通过了
and if we save that away the test should now pass
他们确实做到了
and indeed they do
这就是使用外部库的全部内容
and that's all there is to using an external library